Leeya Davis Software Engineer

I am a software engineer with multiple years of experience with Ruby, Javascript, various front-end and back-end frameworks, and other technologies. I am a co-creator of Twine $\mathscr E$, an open-source solution for managing WebSockets at scale with connection state recovery.

EXPERIENCE

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Twine

08/2023 – present | Remote

https://twine-realtime.github.io/ ∂

Twine is a scalable drop-in Real-time as a Service that abstracts away the complexity of real-time communication and provides connection state recovery

- Prototyped and built Twine using TypeScript, Socket.IO, and Amazon Web Services (DynamoDB, Elasticache for Redis, EC2, ALB, ELB, CloudFront, S3)
- Drafted solution architecture and initial workflow diagrams
- Participated in the design and implementation of short and long-term storage strategies that facilitate connection state recovery
- Improved long-term state recovery by engineering a more performant database query
- Resolved synchronization issues when scaling Twine by implementing Redis Adaptor logic
- Designed and built Twine's object-oriented client and server libraries; published as NPM packages
- Assisted in the design of the CLI tool that using AWS CloudFormation automates the deployment of Twine and its provisioned AWS cloud infrastructure (Elastic Beanstalk Environment, EC2 instances, Application Load Balancer, IAM roles)
- Collaborated remotely with an international team of four engineers across three time zones
- Authored a technical case study providing an in-depth analysis of Twine's problem domain, system design, and engineering decisions (https://twine-realtime.github.io/#four)

Software Engineer, *Self-Employed*

07/2022 – 08/2023 | Remote

- **Request Inspect,** a Request Bin clone for viewing webhooks built with Node.js, MongoDB, Express, React, Nginx, WebSockets, Ngrok
- Contact Manager with dynamic filtering built with Node.js, MongoDB, Express, React, Nginx, DO droplet
- Todo Tracker, a single page application for managing todos built with Ruby, PostgreSQL, Sinatra, ERB, Heroku

Data Processing Coordinator, NYC Department of Health

12/2019 – 07/2022 | New York City

- Coordinated with Opioid Overdose Prevention Programs to ensure timely and accurate report submission.
- Coordinated with unit staff to ensure efficient processing of monthly report components.

Eligibility Verification Specialist, NYC Human Resources Administration

06/2017 – 12/2018 | New York City

Maximized revenue generation for both NYC & outside Agencies by ensuring payments were categorically eligible for their respective funding streams

SKILLS

Front End

JavaScript, React, HTML/CSS, Typescript, Handlebars, Sinatra

Misc. Technologies

Git/Github, Docker, OOP, Nginx, VS Code, Redis, Jest, Webhooks, HTTP, WebSockets, Postman, Mongoose, Bash

Back End

Node.js, Ruby, Express, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, REST APIs, TypeScript, Go

Cloud

MongoDB Atlas, AWS (DynamoDB, Elasticache for Redis, EC2, ALB, ELB, CloudFront, IAM, S3), DigitalOcean droplets, Heroku, Fly.io

EDUCATION

Launch School, https://launchschool.com/employers @

08/2019 - 08/2023

Multi-year, mastery-based software engineering curriculum, with assessment-driven progression in the form of written exams and live coding interviews aimed at developing problem-solving skills.

A.O.S, Occupational Studies, Swedish Institute College of Health Sciences

09/2005 – 12/2006 New York